Guide to the Divinity School Reference Collection, 1926-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
Divinity School Reference collection 1926-ongoing
Duke University. University Archives
3.5 linear feet Extent: 2500 Items
Founded in 1926 as the first of the university's graduate professional schools, the Divinity School attracts students from around the nation and several different countries. One of 13 seminaries founded and supported by the United Methodist Church, the school has from its beginnings been ecumenical in aspiration, teaching, and practice. With many diverse theological perspectives, students find common ground through immersion in Scripture and the church's tradition for addressing the challenges of faith in today's world. Collection contains subject files relating to the Divinity School at Duke University. Some major topics include admissions, sermons, symposiums, continuing education, field education, student groups, and other topics. Video cassettes and audio cassettes are also present in the collection.
UA.01.11.0048
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Divinity School Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Subject Headings
Duke University. Divinity School; Duke University. School of Religion; Duke University. Divinity School -- History; Pastoral theology -- Study and teaching; Theological seminaries -- United States; Theology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- North Carolina; Audiocasttes; Videocassttes
Related Material
Divinity School records, 1925-2005.
University Archives, Duke University.
Elbert Russell papers, 1893-1968.
University Archives, Duke University.
Field Education Program records, 1926-1971.
University Archives, Duke University.
Hilrie Shelton Smith papers, 1941-1983.
University Archives, Duke University.
Junaluska School of Religion records, 1928-1941.
University Archives, Duke University.
Thor Hall papers, 1961-1972.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1926-ongoing, 6 Boxes
  - Administration, 1925-1978 (Box 1)
  - Admissions, 1965-1977 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Affairs, 1970-1990 (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries, 60th (Box 1)
  - Anniversaries, 95th, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Balance Sheet, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Baptist House of Studies, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Bicentennial Celebration [of the North Carolina and the Western Carolina Conferences of the United Methodist Church], 1976 (Box 1)
  - Black Church Studies, 1973-1980 (Box 1)
  - Black Seminarians Union, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
  - Building Addition, 1962-1970 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Career Opportunities, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Chapel Worship Committee, 1969; 1973 (Box 1)
  - Christian Missions Symposium, 1953-1963 (Box 1)
  - Christian Origins Symposium, 1972 (Box 1)
  - "Christianity and Social Revolution in Newly Developed Nations," 9-12 April 1964 (Box 1)
  - Classes [Class of 1934] (Box 1)
  - Clippings, circa 1957-2001 (Box 1)
  - Commencement, 1947-1968 (Box 1)
  - Committee for Christian Social Action, 1979 (Box 2)
  - Concerned Students of Duke Divinity School, 1969; 1979 (Box 2)
  - Concilium newsletter, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Conferences and Symposiums (Misc.), 1960; 1966; 1978-1979 (Box 2)
  - Conference, “Christianity and Social Revolution in Newly Developing Nations,” April 9-12, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Continuing Education (Box 2)
  - Continuing Education for Ministry, 1973-1977 (Box 2)
  - Convocation, Opening of Academic Year-Divinity School (Annual); not Convocation and Pastor's School, 1938; 1950-1972 (Box 2)
  - 1st Convocation, clippings, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Convocations – Closing, circa 1963-2005 (Box 2)
  - Convocation and Pastor's School, 1946-Ongoing (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Coordinating Council for Community Life, undated; 1964-1968 (Box 3)
  - Courses of Study School, 1970-1981 (Box 3)
  - Convocation Worship, 1967, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum: D.Min program, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Curriculum: Master of Theology Program, 1959- (Box 3)
  - Curriculum: Ministering in Context, undated (Box 3)
  - Curriculum: Spiritual Formation (Box 3)
  - Dean, 1947; 1960-1979 (Box 3)
  - Deans, Installation, circa 1951-1997 (Box 3)
  - Dean's Club [Address by Dr. Harvie Branscomb], 1983 (Box 3)
  - The Dean’s Letter, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
  - Divinity Choir, undated (Box 3)
  - Divinity School Worship Book (Box 3)
  - Educational Affairs Council, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
  - Endowment Newsletter, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Endowment and Fundraising: The Gilbert T. Rowe Scholarship Fund Plan of Campaign, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - Endowment and Fundraising, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Advisors, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Faculty Bulletin, 1958-1971(3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Field Education, undated; 1969; 1973 (Box 4)
  - Financial Aid, undated (Box 4)
  - Formal Opening, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Gay and Lesbian Issues, 2003-Ongoing (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - History and Bibliography (Box 4)
  - History, Account of the Naming of the Divinity School (Box 4)
  - Intergenerational Christian Education, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Interseminary Conference, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Kearns Fellowship, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Gardner C. Taylor Preaching and Lecture Series, 1995, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Gray and Hickman Lectures (Box 4)
  - Kenneth W. Clark Lectures (Box 4)
  - Last Lectures Series [Thomas A. Langford], 1997 (Box 4)
  - Lecture Program, 1950-1979 (Box 4)
  - Library Lecture, 1950-1961 (Box 4)
  - Library, 1946; 1973-1975 (Box 5)
  - Jordan Loan Library, undated; 1954 (Box 5)
  - Logo, undated (Box 5)
  - Lucretia Mott Feminist Caucus, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Operation Love, circa 1978 (Box 5)
  - Divinity School [Orientation Program], 1969 (Box 5)
  - Pastors' School, 1938; 1947-1969 (Box 5)
  - Phillips Brooks Club, undated (Box 5)
  - Race Relations and the Divinity School, undated; 1951; 1963 (Box 5)
  - School of Religion Association, undated; 1931-1932 (Box 5)
  - Self-Study Report, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Self-Study Commission Records, 1970-1971 (Box 5)
  - Self-Study, 1970 (Box 5)
  - School Seminars, 1959-1973 (Box 5)
  - Seminar on Visiting the Homebound, Report 1965 (Box 5)
  - Seminars in Virginia and South Carolina, 1966-1967; 1973 (Box 5)
  - Service of Worship, Misc. Services, 1950-1972 (Box 5)
  - "Seven Great Universities," undated (Box 6)
  - Society of New Testament Scholars, 1976 (Box 6)
  - The Sojourner, 1980 (Box 6)
  - Student Body Activity Report, 1939-1940 (Box 6)
  - Student Bulletin, 1964-1971 (Box 6)
  - Student Pastor Association, 1975 (Box 6)
  - Student Pastors, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Student Representative Assembly, 1969-1975 (Box 6)
  - Theta Phi (Box 6)
  - United Methodism and American Culture, 1993 (Box 6)
  - Women’s Center (Box 6)
  - Women's Council and Women Divinity Students, 1976-1977 (Box 6)
  - York Chapel Organ Dedication, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Faculty writings and articles, undated
    - Clark, Kenneth W. Four decades of the Divinity School, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Daily, Daniel, Donn Michael Farris: Theological Librarian of Duke University Divinity School, 1994 [Master's paper, SILS-UNC-CH; 10 audiocassettes, duplication masters] (Box 6)
    - Davies, Merlin C. Racial Segregation in Christian Higher Education, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Davies, Merlin C. Racial Segregation in Christian Higher Education, (Originals), 1952 (Box 6)
    - Gray, Stephen C. Crest Street Tutors: Educational Retribution for a Black Community?, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Longfield, Bradley J. Eruditio et Religio: Religion at Duke Between the World Wars, 1991, 1996 (Box 6)
    - A Witness to the Event, from The Divinity School Community, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Divinity School: Sharing a Vision, 1989 VHS cassette (11 minutes) (2 copies + DVD duplication master) (Videotape 1)
  - Duke Divinity School: A School of the Church, A School of the University, 1995 VHS cassette + DVD duplication master (Videotape 2)
  - Dean Dennis Campbell, Last Lecture, 18 April 1997, Audiocassette; duplication master (Box 6, Audiocassette 1)
  - Dr. Gayle Felton, Last Lecture, 7 March 1997, Audiocassette; duplication master (Box 6, Audiocassette 2)
  - Dr. Thomas Langford, Last Lecture, 11 April 1997, Audiocassette; duplication master (Box 6, Audiocassette 3)
  - Marty Smith, Interview, 16 June 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 4)
  - Loyd, 21 June 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 5)
  - Donn Michael Farris, Interview, 27 May 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 6)
  - Donn Michael Farris, Interview, 6 April 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 7)
  - Donn Michael Farris, Interview, 30 March 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 8)
  - Donn Michael Farris, Interview, 16 March 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 9)
  - Donn Michael Farris, Interview, 17 February 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 10)
  - Dr. Jerry Campbell, Interview, 2 May 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 11)
  - Dean Dennis Campbell, Interview, 25 May 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 12)
  - Florence Blakely, Interview, 5 April 1994, Audiocassette (Box 6, Audiocassette 13)